Let's go through the concept of the marketing funnel.
让我们了解一下什么是营销漏斗
Now that we understand the journey a potential customer goes through,
刚才 我们解释了潜在客户经过的客户旅程
we can use the metaphor of a funnel to track
我们可以利用漏斗来比喻
and analyze each step in the journey with data.
用数据追踪和分析客户旅程的过程
Impressions and reach capture the person seeing the ad.
广告的展现量(impressions) 和 到达率(reach) 决定了看到广告的潜在用户人数
Lead generation is visiting the website,
潜在客户是指点击浏览网站的人
and buying something is conversion to a paid customer.
而在购买商品后 潜在客户便转化为付费客户
So, at the top, we're trying to build
在漏斗的顶端 我们要努力让更多人知道我们的存在
awareness and get our name in front of the potential customer.
让潜在客户知道并记住我们产品的名字
To do this, we use ad platforms and search engine optimization or SEO.
为此 我们借助广告平台或搜索引擎优化 (后者简称 SEO)
With SEO, we can make sure our ad shows up for
利用 SEO 技术 确保当人们在网上搜索某些关键词时
the right mix of search terms as people are searching for things online.
就会看到我们的广告
For example, search terms like grocery delivery or grocery shopping
例如 当用户搜索“日常用品网购”或“日常用品送到家”之类的关键词
would be a good search term when we cart it ad shows up for the person.
就是给他显示 WeCart 广告的好时机
The metrics we can measure here are the number of people who saw the ad.
这里的关键指标是 — 看到这则广告的总人数
Some of those people will click the ad and be taken to our website.
部分人会点击广告 从而进入我们的网站
To be counted at this level,
在漏斗的这一层
the user should have clicked through the ad or the email sent to them.
用户应该是点击了广告或邮件中的链接才进入网站的
The metrics we use here are called click-through rate and cost per click.
这里涉及两个指标 — 点进率、平均点击成本
At this third level,
在漏斗的第三层
the user has been counted because they have visited the company website.
当用户浏览了公司网站时 便计入人数
But just because someone landed on your web page,
但仅仅是浏览了网页
that does not mean the person is interested in
不代表他真的会花钱
spending money on buying a product from your website.
从网站上购买商品
More sites try to capture some other piece of information
有些网站会努力收集用户的其他信息
about you to determine if you're indeed interested.
来确定用户是否真的对他们的产品感兴趣
The most common is your email.
最常见的是收集你的电子邮箱地址
With your email, they will then have the ability to send
那样 他们便能给你发送营销邮件
your marketing emails to try and convert you into a paying customer.
来试图将你转化为付费客户
If you provide your email or any other piece of information about yourself,
如果你填写了电邮地址或者其他个人信息
you have indicated interest in the business,
就说明你对那家公司的产品感兴趣
and the business will now think of you as a potential customer.
那家公司便会把你视为潜在客户
They call this a lead.
也称为 lead
Other ways that businesses gauge your interests
公司要判断你是否对他们的产品有兴趣
are if you download a document or create an account.
还可以查看你是否下载了文档或创建了账户
Once visitors engage in any of these actions,
一旦浏览网站的用户进行了上述任何操作
the user is counted as a lead.
用户就被视为潜在客户
At this level, marketing teams often want to know how much
在这一个层面上 营销团队通常会设法了解
it costs a business to get the viewers to get to this level.
公司要花多少成本才能让任何一个普通人成为潜在用户
The metric we calculate is the cost per lead.
此时 所需计算的指标是 — 平均潜在用户获得成本
The final step is when the customer actually
最后一步是当客户实际下单购买商品
makes a purchase and becomes a paid customer.
成为付费客户
In other words, the lead converted to a paid customer.
也就是说 成功把潜在客户转化为付费客户
Our ultimate goal is to maximize these conversions at the bottom of the funnel.
我们的最终目标是使更多的用户达到漏斗的底端
In the following pages,
接下来
we will address each of
我们会探讨漏斗每一层当中
these specific metrics that capture the progress at each of these levels.
能够实际体现进展情况的每一项指标
We will go over how to calculate them,
我们会先讲解如何计算这些指标
and then you will practice.
接着进行练习巩固
Now that you have an overview of this customer journey,
現在你已经了解了客户旅程的大致概念
calculating these metrics is not going to be hard.
要计算这些指标就不会很难